Thongo lam vuma, Lam vuma, Lam vuma, lam vuma. (Improvising) (Music ends) (Applause) Thandiswa Mazwai: Hello everybody. Thank you so much for having us here. My name is Thandiswa Mazwai. I am a wild woman, a rebel singer, a conduit. My music is about memory and struggling between oppresion and freedom. After over 20 years in South Africa we find ourselves as the black masses still suffering and fighting for our freedom and humanity. This first song was called "Iyeza" which means "medicine." Medicine for our madness, medicine for our rage. This song we're doing now is called "Zabalaza," and it means "rebel." I'd like to dedicate this to the valiant student movement in South Africa who came up with the #FeesMustFall. (Applause) Rhodes Must Fall. But more importantly, the new vigor that has been brought into the feminist movement so patriarchy must fall.
Thongo lam vum Thongo lam vuma Lam vuma Lam vuma, lam vuma (Improvisation) (Fin de la chanson) (Applaudissements) Bonjour à tous ! Merci beaucoup de nous recevoir ici. Je m'appelle Thandiswa Mazwai. Je suis une femme sauvage, une chanteuse rebelle, une messagère. Ma musique traite des mémoires et du combat entre l'oppression et la liberté. Après plus de 20 ans en Afrique du Sud, nous, toute la communauté noire, souffrons et combattons encore pour notre liberté et humanité. La première chanson s’appelait « Iyeza » qui signifie « remède ». Remède contre notre folie, Remède contre notre colère Celle que nous allons chanter maintenant s'appelle « Zabalaza » qui signifie « Révolté ». J'aimerais la dédier au brave mouvement étudiant d'Afrique du Sud qui est à l'origine de #FeesMustFall (Applaudissements) #RhodesMustFall Mais plus important, la nouvelle détermination dans le mouvement féministe, donc la patriarchie doit tomber.
(Applause) (Music) Gogo bek' umthwalo Kunin' uhlupheka? Little ghetto child Ungazibulali sana Oh ... If you take my hand, I'll show you
(Applaudissements) (Musique) Gogo bek' umthwalo Kunin' uhlupheka ? Little ghetto child (Petit enfant du ghetto) Ungazibulali sana Oh ... Si tu prends ma main, Je te montrerais
how to be free. Ayifanelang' ub' iyenzeka lento Emzini kabawo kunge kudala Sizozabalaza. Zabalaza, zabalaza. Zabalaza. Sizozabalaza. Zabalaza, zabalaza. Zabalaza. (Vocalizing) (Improvising) It's my people in Soweto, my people in Mozambique, my people in Senegal. These are my people in the ghettos. Zabalaza, zabalaza. Zabalaza. (Music ends) (Applause) (Cheering) Thank you very much. (Applause)
comment être libre. Ayifanelang' ub' iyenzeka lento Emzini kabawo kunge kudala Sizozabalaza. Zabalaza, zabalaza. Zabalaza. Sizozabalaza. Zabalaza, zabalaza. Zabalaza. (Vocalisation) (Improvisation) C'est mon peuple à Soweto, C'est mon peuple en Mozambique, mon peuple au Sénégal. C'est mon peuple dans les ghettos. Zabalaza, zabalaza. Zabalaza. (Fin de la chanson) (Applaudissements) (Acclamations) Merci infiniment. (Applaudissements)